verizonbusiness.com 2006-12-05

# Verizon | About Verizon - Privacy and Customer Security Policies - Internet Privacy

What information does this Web site gather?  
Verizon collects personal information such as name, address, and email address, when you knowingly provide it to us. In addition, Verizon may collect other information provided by you, such as your credit card number, billing address, Social Security Number (SSN) and date of birth, when you set up an online account or order service online. Our Web servers automatically collect statistical information about your visit such as pages visited and which browsers are used to visit our site. None of this information is associated with you as an individual (see information about cookies). We use these statistics to monitor our site's performance and to make it easier for you to use. 

If you choose to use an available referral service to tell a friend about our site or a specific product or service, we will ask for your friend's name and email address. We will then send your friend a one-time email regarding our site or the featured product or service. Verizon uses this information for purposes of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of the referral service. 

Back to Top

What happens when I provide personal information on this Web site?  
When you supply information for a specific purpose, such as online ordering of a Verizon service, we use the information for that purpose. 

When you use our Web site to order services, we may use this individually identifiable information as we would if obtained in a non-electronic manner. Such information may include:

 •  Publishing your name, address, and phone number in our directories (unless you have requested  
a non-published or non-listed number)  
 •  Evaluating your service needs and contacting you regarding additional services you may find useful

If the way we use personally identifiable information changes, Verizon will contact you via email notifying you of this change and giving you the opportunity to opt out of such use. 

Back to Top

What happens when I provide information on registration forms?  
When you choose to register with verizon.com or any other Verizon site, we request accurate contact information and preferences that help us better serve you. You will always retain the option to choose if your contact information is used to send you company and product information, special offers, and in some cases, newsletters. 

If you're a local Verizon phone service customer, you may be given the option to register a profile with us (limited to specific areas). We would then store your name, purchase history, and billing information to make it easier for you to shop and purchase from us in the future. Customers have access to their account information on their monthly bills or by establishing an [account online](https://www22.verizon.com/myaccount/). 

At anytime you may:

 •  Elect not to receive (opt out) marketing email messages. The primary purpose of these messages   
is the commercial advertisement or promotion of a Verizon product or service. At any time after the   
initial registration, you can opt out by selecting the opt-out cancel option in your profile within the   
application itself.  
 •  Update your contact and personal information anytime by updating your account and/or your profile   
(where available) within the application.

In order to improve your experience with us, we may decide to improve our site's ability to obtain information about users. We will update this privacy statement continually to ensure that you are aware of developments in this area. 

Back to Top

Does Verizon sell or give my information to non-Verizon companies?  
No. We do not sell or disclose individually identifiable information obtained online about our visitors to anyone outside of Verizon. The only exceptions to this rule are the following:

 •  If you specifically authorize Verizon to share your information with another company  
 •  It is required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or  
to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site  
 •  Disclosure is necessary to protect the safety of customers, employees, or property  
 •  Publishing your name, address, and phone number in our directories if you initiate your telephone  
service with us online (unless you have requested a non-published or non-listed number)  
 •  Sharing data with our authorized vendors, contractors and agents, only to the extent necessary for  
them to perform their work, in order that Verizon can carry out certain functions in marketing and  
delivering services to you.

If you provide individually identifiable information at an event Verizon sponsors with another company, or if you register on a co-sponsored Web site, or if you have elected to participate in an affinity program (such as airline miles), you may be providing the individually identifiable information to the co-sponsor as well as Verizon. Review the privacy statement at the event or on the co-branded site or the affinity site to learn how the partner uses this information. Be assured that Verizon uses this information in accordance with this privacy policy. 

On occasion, Verizon shares non-personally identifiable information with non-Verizon companies in order to assess the results of a promotion or event. This information is used in aggregate only, and does not contain any information that would personally identify you. 

Back to Top

Does Verizon accommodate links to other sites?  
Yes. Our site contains links to other Web sites. We are not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by other sites. However, in some instances where a service is provided through a non-Verizon partner or supplier site, such as Online Bill Pay, you can feel confident that your individually identifiable information will be protected. Verizon requires suppliers not to use the information for any purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected, protecting the privacy of your information. 

Back to Top

What does Verizon do with non-personally identifiable information collected automatically?  
Verizon uses cookies to collect this type of information in order to enhance your online experience as follows:

 •  Ensure that you see the correct products and pricing applicable to the state in which you live  
 •  Manage the number of ads that you see to avoid over-delivery of the same message  
 •  Tailor an advertisement to better match your interests and preferences 

Back to Top

What does Verizon do with personally identifiable information?  
Personal information you voluntarily supply when obtaining information, purchasing products, or interacting with our advertising on verizon.com **is not shared** for non-Verizon purposes. This information is Verizon proprietary data and is not available for use to any outside company in this personalized form. Should any changes be made in the way we use personally identifiable information, Verizon will contact you via email notifying you of this change and give you the opportunity to choose to opt out of such use. 

Back to Top

Does Verizon use the information provided online to profile its customers?  
No. Verizon does not combine offline information about you with the online information that you provide on our Web site. 

We have made it a requirement that you will be clearly notified at the time of online data collection for the purpose of consumer profiling. When your online purchase behavior is intended to be combined with offline information, this intent will be clearly stated. You will then have the ability to choose not to have that information combined. 

Back to Top

|  Does this site send email to site visitors?  
Verizon strives to continuously improve our customers' online experience by providing them with the latest information about the benefits of Verizon's products and services and in other circumstances described below. We may provide this information in any number of ways, including emails to our customers, online visitors and others who have provided their email addresses to Verizon. In addition, unless you have chosen to opt out from receiving email messages from Verizon, Verizon may send emails to: 

 •  Inform customers that their telephone bills are available for review online  
 •  Conduct online surveys  
 •  Provide marketing information about Verizon products and services  
 •  Provide information to those who have voluntarily provided their email addresses to third parties in  
order to receive promotional material

Moreover, in the following situations, Verizon reserves the right to communicate through email with online users, including those who have opted out of receiving solicitation-based emails, to:

 •  Notify customers about service or product affecting changes  
 •  Respond to an online user's email  
 •  Confirm transactions, orders, payments and registrations placed online  
 •  Send information that a customer or potential customer has requested  
 •  Provide emergency, security and online account maintenance information

Verizon supports and complies with all laws governing its email communications and will update this policy as needed to ensure ongoing compliance. 

Back to Top

|  What are cookies and why does Verizon use them?  
A cookie is a small data string our server writes to your hard drive. This data string contains your unique user ID for our Web site. This technology also allows us to customize your experiences when you visit the Verizon Web site. For example, we're able to deliver content specific to your interests, keep track of your online ordering and alert you to new products or money saving opportunities based on your current services. 

Back to Top

What information is collected by the site or in cookies?  
Verizon collects non-personally identifiable information regarding your visit, usually in the form of cookies, log files, or clear .gif files. Cookies contain a session identification number that our systems use to recall previous authentication or order information from our servers. We may also collect your domain name, IP address, the address of the last URL you visited prior to coming to our Web site, and your browser and platform type. We use third party tracking services to help us analyze this information in the aggregate to evaluate the effectiveness of our site. In some cases, the information is collected directly by the third party and in others it is forwarded by Verizon to the third party. The third party is not permitted to use the information for any other purpose. 

Back to Top

How do I disable cookies on my browser?  
It's important you know that a cookie cannot be used to access or otherwise compromise the data on your hard drive. Your privacy is always protected. However, at any time you may choose to change your browser settings to disable cookies if you do not want us to establish and maintain a unique verizon.com user ID for you. Please be aware that cookies may be required to complete certain functions on this Web site, such as ordering online. We've made it easy for you to remove cookies from your browser. Simply choose from the list below and click on the name of the browser you use to access the Internet to find instructions.

Back to Top

|  What is Verizon's position regarding online advertising and third-party ad servers?  
As an online advertiser, Verizon uses information supplied from third-party companies in several ways. This is aggregated data that does not personally identify any individual online user. This data is used to:

 •  Evaluate and prioritize site selection when developing online media plans  
 •  Geographically target advertising  
 •  Deliver product and pricing information applicable to the customer's state  
 •  Gauge the effectiveness of our online advertising

Again, personally identifiable information such as name, address, phone number, or email address is not collected unless you voluntarily supply this data to Verizon or to a third party partner in order to get further information about Verizon products and services. 

In addition, some Verizon Web sites -- for example, www.SuperPages.com \-- may accept advertisements from third-party advertisers. These advertisers are carefully selected to provide information about products and services that we think may benefit you. Please check the privacy policy of these Web sites concerning what information may be collected by third-party advertisers. 

Third-party advertising companies may also utilize technology in order to measure the effectiveness of ads. Some Verizon Web pages contain clear .gif files (also known as Web beacons), electronic images that allow the third party to collect anonymous information. This anonymous information about your visits to our site is used to provide advertisements about goods and services of potential interest to you. No personally identifiable information is collected during this process. 

Back to Top

Whom do I contact if I am concerned, or have questions, about my Privacy at Verizon?  
Please visit Contact Us. 

Back to Top

Updated January 2006
